made by 돗치우드
디씨인사이드 영국드라마갤러리
-닥터-
데이비드 테넌트
-도나 노블-
캐서린 테이트
Doctor Who Season 4
E01 - Partners In Crime
aired on 2008.04.05
안녕하세요, 아디포스 물산입니다
Good morning, Adipose Industries.
도나 노블, 건강과 안전을!
Donna Noble, Health and Safety.
존 스미스, 건강과 안전을!
John Smith, Health and Safety.
아디포스 물산입니다
Adipose Industries.
살을 빼는 21세기적 방법이죠
The 21st century way to lose weight.
운동도, 식이요법도,
고통도 없습니다
No exercise, no diet, no pain.
영영 지방으로부터 해방입니다
현대의 성배나 다름없죠
just lifelong freedom from fat,
the Holy Grail of the modern age.
바로 이것입니다
And here it is.
알약 하나만 복용하세요
You just take one capsule.
한 알씩, 하루에 한번
3주면 됩니다
One capsule, once a day, for three weeks.
그러면 지방들이,
어떻게 되는가 하면..
And the fat, as they say...
'지방들이 달아나 버린답니다'
'The fat just walks away.'
실례합니다, 포스터 씨
괜찮겠죠?
Excuse me, Miss Foster, if l could?
페니 카터, '옵저버'지의
과학부 기자입니다
Penny Carter,
Science Correspondent for the Observer.
시중엔 수많은 다이어트제가 있고
사람들을 등쳐먹는 수많은 짜가도 있죠
There are a thousand diet pills,
a thousand conmen stealing people's money.
그 지방들이 당신들의
수작인지 어떻게 알겠어요?
How do we know the fat isn't going
straight into your bank account?
페니 씨, 회의주의는
살 빼는데 도움이 안 돼요
Oh, Penny... If cynicism burnt up calories,
we'd all be thin as rakes.
그랬다면 다들
피골이 상접해 있었겠죠
과학적인 것을 원하신다면야
기꺼이 설명해드리죠
But if you want the science,
I can oblige.
'아디포스 물산입니다'
'Adipose Industries.
'아디포스 캡슐은
유동 리파아제 종합체로'
'The Adipose Capsule is composed of a synthesised
mobilising lipase, 'bound to a large protein molecule.
'큰 단백질 분자에
담겨 있습니다'
유동 리파아제가
트리글리세린을 깨고 나옵니다
'The mobilising lipase breaks up the triglycerides
'stored in the Adipose cells, which then.
'아디포스 세포에 저장되어 있죠
그렇게 되면..'
건강과 안전을,
영화 부서입니다
Health and Safety.
Film department.
100% 합법적이고
100% 효과 보장이죠
100% legal, 100% effective.
그냥 궁금해서 그러는데요
얼마나 많은 사람들이
But can l just ask,
how many people have taken the pills to date?
데이트씩이나 하려고
약을 먹었을까요?
저희는 이미 런던 지역에서만
10만명의 고객을 유치했습니다
We've already got one million customers
within the Greater London area alone...
...But from next week,
we start rolling out nationwide.
그리고 다음 주 부터는
전세계로 영업을 확장할 겁니다
미래가 여기서
시작되는 거죠
The future starts here.
영국은 날씬해 질 겁니다
And Britain will be thin.
안녕하세요, 아디포스 물산입니다
그것은 3주 코스 제품입니다
45파운드의 특별 가격이죠
That's a three-week course of pills
for the special price of 45 pounds.
평일에는 3일 이내로
배달해 드려요
We deliver within three working days.
상품에는 21정의 알약과
정보 책자, 그리고 저희의 특별선물인
The box comes with 21 days' worth of pills,
a full information pack,
and our special free gift,
an Adipose Industries pendant.
아디포스 물산의
펜던트를 드립니다
18캐럿 금으로 되어 있구요
손님들께 무료로 드리고 있어요
It's made of 18-carat gold,
and it's yours for free.
아뇨, 죄송합니다
펜은 안 드려요, 죄송해요
No, we don't give away pens. Sorry.
아뇨, 예외로 쳐 드릴수도 없어요
No, I can't make an exception, no.
이것은 테스트 용으로
가져가야겠어요
I'll need to keep this for testing.
그리고 고객 목록이 필요해요
프린트해 줄 수 있겠어요?
And l just need a list of your customers.
Could you print it off?
- 그럴 것 같네요
- 프린터는 어디에요?
- I suppose so.
- Where's the printer?
바로 저기에요
화분 옆에요
just over there, by the plant.
무슨 화분이요
저 화분이요?
Which plant, that plant?
- 네, 저거에요
- 고마워요
- Yeah, that's the one.
- Lovely.
저 프린터 말하는 거죠?
That's the printer there?
화분 옆에요, 네
By the plant, yeah.
암호가 필요한가요? 지난 번
직장에선, 프린터에 암호가 필요했어요
Does it need a code? Last place I worked,
the printer needed a code.
아뇨, 여기에서 처리해 드릴게요
No, I can do it from here.
용지는 넉넉합니까?
Has it got paper?
네, 신입사원들이
채워 놓아요
Yeah, jimbo keeps it stocked.
실례하겠어요, 여러분
Excuse me, everyone.
잠깐 귀 좀 빌릴 수 있을까요
If I could have your attention.
평균적으로, 여러분은 하루에
40개의 아디포스 팩을 팔고 있죠
On average, you're each selling
40 Adipose packs per day.
충분치가 않아요
한 사람당 하루에 100개씩 파세요
It's not enough.
I want 100 sales per person, per day.
못 하시겠다면
다른 사람을 쓰겠어요
And if not, you'll be replaced.
살 다루기를 잘 하는 사람이라면
저밖에 없으니까요
Cos if anyone's good at trimming the fat,
it's me.
자.. 일들 하세요
Now... Back to it.
어쨌든, 프린트 좀 해 주세요
고마워요
Anyway, If you could print that off, thanks.
저 목록좀 인쇄해 주시겠어요
그러면 방해하지 않을게요
So if you could print off that list,
I'll get out of your way.
좋군요, 고마워요. 또 봐요!
Lovely. Thanks, then.
See you!
고맙습니다 그럼
우, 이게 뭡니까?
Thanks, then. Ooh,
what's that?
- 제 전화번호에요
- 뭣하러요?
- My telephone number.
- What for?
건강과 안전을!
Health and Safety.
당신은 건강해지고
전 안전해 지겠죠
You be health. I'll be safety.
아! 하지만 그건 사내 규약
5절 C항에 위반이에요, 미안해요
Ah! But that contravenes paragraph 5,
subsection C. Sorry.
다시 왔어요!
Me again!
- 스테이시 캠벨 씨?
- 누구시죠?
- Stacy Campbell?
- Who wants to know?
전 도나이고
아디포스 물산에서 나왔습니다
My name's Donna, I represent Adipose Industries,
and you're on the list of our valued customers.
저희 우수 고객 명단에
드셨더군요
로저 데이비 씨! 저는 아디포스
물산에서 나왔습니다만
Mr Roger Davey! I'm calling on behalf of Adipose
Industries, just need to ask you a few questions.
여쭤볼 게 있어서 왔습니다
정말 효과가 좋아요
It's been fantastic.
목요일에 약을 시작했어요
I started the pills on Thursday.
5일이 지나니까
11파운드가 빠졌어요
Five days later,
I've lost 11 pounds.
부작용 같은 것은
없으셨나요?
And no side effects or anything?
없어요. 기분이 끝내줘요
No, l feel fantastic.
새 삶이 시작된거에요
It's a new lease of life.
이 귀걸이들 어떤것 같아요
잘 먹힐까요?
Now what do you think about these earrings,
do they work?
네, 예뻐요
Yeah, lovely.
2주째 약을 복용중인데
14킬로가 빠졌습니다
I've been on the pills two weeks now,
I've lost 14 kilos.
매일 같은 양이요?
The same amount every day?
정확히 1키로씩이죠. 일어나면
밤 사이에 사라져 있답니다
One kilo exactly. You wake up,
and it's disappeared overnight.
음, 정확히 말하자면
새벽 1시 10분에 사라지죠
Well, technically speaking, it's
gone by ten past one in the morning.
왜 그렇게 말씀하시지요?
What makes you say that?
그 때 깨거든요
That's when I get woken up.
동시에 매일 같은 시간
몸무게를 재어 본답니다!
Might as well weigh myself at the same time!
데이트 하러 가시는 건가요?
Are you going on a date?
정 반대에요
그를 차버릴 거에요!
I'm doing the opposite,
I'm dumping him!
이제 더 나은 사람을
만날 수 있으니까요
I can do better than him now.
자, 오래 걸리지 않을 거에요
Right, I won't be long.
택시가 빵빵거리면
저 좀 불러 주세요
If the taxi beeps, give me a shout.
그것 때문에 미치겠습니다
It is driving me mad.
밤 1시 10분만 되면, 매일 밤
한 치 오차도 없이 정각에
Ten minutes past one, every night, bang on
the dot without fail, the burglar alarm goes off.
도난 알람이 울려요
전문가도 불러봤고, 갈아도 보고
경호업체에도 전화해 봤어요
I've had experts in, I've had it replaced,
I've even phoned Watchdog.
하지만 안 됐어요! 새벽
1시 10분에 늘 울려요
But no!
Ten past one in the morning, off it goes.
하지만 도둑은 없었구요?
- But with no burglars?
- Nothing! I've given up looking.
아무것도요!
이젠 찾는것도 포기했어요
말씀해 주시죠, 로저 씨
Tell me, Roger.
'들구멍'이 있으신가요?
Have you got a cat flap?
집을 샀을 때 부터 있었어요
It was here when I bought the house.
신경 써 본적이 없어요
I've never bothered with it.
전 고양이 인간이 아니니까요
I'm not a cat person.
네, 고양이 인간들은 만나봤어요
No, I've met cat people.
당신은 전혀 닮지 않았어요
You're nothing like them.
이것때문에 그런 건가요?
Is that what it is?
고양이들이 집에 들어오는 건가?
Cats getting inside the house?
글쎄요, 들구멍이 중요한 이유는
뭔가 들어오기 때문만은 아니죠
Well, the thing about cat flaps is they don't
just let things in, they let things out as well.
뭔가가 나가기도 하니까요
어떤 것들요?
Like what?
'지방들이 달아나 버린답니다'
The fat just walks away.
- 곧 갈게요!
- 괜찮아요
- Won't be long!
- That's all right.
예정에 없던 출산이 생겼다
We have unscheduled parthenogenesis.
네, 도와주셔서 감사합니다
Well, thanks for your help.
충고드리는데요, 한 일주일
정도는 약을 안 드셔도 되겠어요
Tell you what, maybe you could
lay off the pills for a week or so.
가야겠어요, 미안해요!
Gotta go, sorry!
'수집 부대'를 출동시켜라
Send out the Collection Squad.
그들을 집으로 데려와
Bring them home.
- 거기 위에 괜찮아요?
- 네
- Are you alright up there?
- Yeah.
'아디포스'가 노출되었다
The Adipose has been witnessed.
생식을 최대로 활성시켜
'Activating full parthenogenesis
너희들 뭐야?
너네 뭐야?
What are you? What are you?
시청에서 하셨던 일이 마음에 드네요
I like what you've done with the hall.
스테이시?
Stacy?
괜찮아요?
Are you all right?
잠깐 올라가봐도 괜찮겠지요
I wouldn't mind a little visit myself.
거기 안에 괜찮아요?
Everything all right in there?
저에요
It's only me.
화장실 좀 써도 괜찮을까요?
Do you mind if I pop to the loo?
스테이시?
Stacy?
도와줘요!
맙소사, 도와주세요!
Help me! Oh, my God, help me!
왜 그래요? 무슨 일이에요?
What is it? What's wrong?
스테이시!
Stacy!
스테이시 캠벨이죠?
Stacy Campbell?
- 아뇨, 그녀는 사라졌어요
- 어디로 갔나요?
- No. She's gone.
- Gone where?
- 그냥 사라졌다니까요
- 오, 그래요. 무지 고맙군요
- She's just gone.
- Oh, great Thanks for nothing.
우리 회사에
산업 스파이가 있는 것 같군요
It seems we have a case of industrial espionage.
만지기만 하면 주인에 맞춰
생물 적응이 될텐데
One touch and the capsule
bio-tunes itself to its owner,
but someone must have introduced a second,
raw capsule.
그러니 누군가 분명 두 번째,
날것의 캡슐을 반출했어
그러니까, 이 작자들 중
하나가 도둑이겠지
Therefore, one of these people is a thief.
저기! 오, 그래..
There! Oh, yes.
저 여자군. 그럼..
There she is. Now...
저 여자를 어쩐다?
What shall we do with her?
지금이 대체 몇 시니?
And what time's this?
내가 몇 살인데 그래!
How old am I?!
핸드폰 쓰기에는 아직 어리지
Not old enough to use a phone.
네가 몇 주 정도만 돌아온 줄
알았다. 너 좀 봐라!
I thought you were only moving
back for a couple of weeks. Look at you!
이러다간 집 못 구할거야
실직 수당 받는 동안엔 말야
You're never gonna find a flat,
not while you're on the dole.
거기 앉아서 구직자처럼 차려입고
있어봤자 쓸데없어. 일을 해야지
It's no good sitting there dressed up looking
like you're job-hunting, you've got to do something.
80년대 같지를 않아서 요즘은
아무도 백수는 안 해, 너 빼고
It's not like the 1980s. No-one's
unemployed these days, except you.
그 '건강과 안전을'이라는 데는
얼마나 있었더라?
How long did that job with Health and Safety last?
이틀이었지, 그러고는
그만둬 버렸잖아
Two days, and then you walk out.
'다른 계획이 있어'
'I have other plans.'
글쎄, 아직은 모르겠다만
Well, I've not seen them.
거기 멍하니 앉아있지 말라니까
마법 지팡이로 네 삶을 바꿔줄 사람은
아무도 없을게야
And it's no good sitting there dreaming, no-one's gonna
come along with a magic wand and make your life all better.
할아버지는 어디있어?
Where's Grandad?
어디 있을 것 같니?
Where d'you think he is?
언덕 위에 있지!
Up the hill!
맨날 언덕 위에 계시잖니!
He's always up the hill!
아이구야, 우리 말썽쟁이 오셨네
Aye-aye. Here comes trouble.
승선 허가를 부탁드립니다, 선장님
Permission to board ship, sir.
허가한다
Permission granted.
엄마가 잔소리 하든?
Was she nagging you?
아하! 재밌었어요
A-ha! Big time.
- 보온병 가져 왔어요
- 오, 고맙다
- Brought you a Thermos.
- Oh, ta.
뭐 좀 보셨어요?
You seen anything?
그래, 비너스를 봤단다
겉보기 등급이 -3.5야
Yeah, I've got Venus,
with an apparent magnitude of minus 3.5.
적어도 그건 내 책에 적힌 대로란다
자, 와서 보렴
At least, that's what it says
in my little book. Here, come and see.
이리 와, 보렴
Come on, off you go.
보이니?
Right?
태양계에서 유일하게
여성의 이름을 딴 행성이야
That's the only planet in the solar system
named after a woman.
그녀는 좋겠네요
Good for her.
얼마나 멀리 떨어져 있죠?
How far away is that?
260만 마일정도 돼
It's about 26 million miles.
언젠가는 우리도 갈 수 있을 게다
But we'll get there one day.
100년 안에 우리는 별들 사이를
다니고 있을게다
100 years' time,
we'll be striding out amongst the stars,
jiggling about with all them aliens,
just you wait.
외계인들과 돌아다니면서 말이다
기다려 보렴
그런 것들을 정말
믿으시나봐요, 네?
You really believe in all that stuff,
don't you?
요즘은 어디든지
널려 있잖냐
They're all over the place these days.
내가 여기서 충분히
오래 기다릴 수만 있다면..
If I wait here long enough...
혹시 조그만 파란 상자를
본 적은 없는 것 같으세요?
Don't suppose you've seen a little blue box?
그거 무슨 신조어냐?
Is that slang for something?
아뇨, 말 그대로에요
No, I mean it.
만일 저 하늘에서 날아다니는
조그만 파랑 상자를 보신다면
If you ever see a little blue box flying
up there in the sky, you shout for me, Gramps.
저 좀 불러 주세요, 할아버지
오, 소리만 치시면 돼요
Oh, you just shout.
그거 아니, 네가 말하는 거
절반도 못 알아 듣겠다, 요즘은
D'you know, I don't understand
half the things you say these days.
- 저도 그래요
- 그래, 그럴만 하지
Nor me. No, fair dos.
최근 좀 이상한 일을
많이 겪었잖니
You've had a funny old time of it lately.
그 불쌍한 젊은이 누구더라,
란스, 불쌍한 것
There was poor old whats his name,
Lance, bless him.
그 요란한 크리스마스 말이다
That barmy old Christmas.
내막이 뭔지 네가
말해 주었으면 한단다
I wish you'd tell us what really happened.
저도 알아요
I know.
그러니까 그게..
It's just...
제가 본 것들이란..
The things I've seen.
가끔 제가 미쳐가는게 아닌가 싶어요
Sometimes I think I'm going mad.
그게요, 오늘 밤도,
저는 그러니까..
I mean, even tonight, I was in a...
신경쓰지 마세요
Doesn't matter.
글쎄, 평소같지는 않구나
그건 확실하네
Well, you're not yourself,
I'll give you that.
너는 있지..
You just...
요즘 방황하는 것 같구나, 얘야
You seem to be drifting, sweetheart.
방황하는 게 아녜요
I'm not drifting.
- 기다리고 있어요 / 뭘?
- 어떤 남자를요
- I'm waiting.
- What for?
The right man.
오!
Oh!
옛날 이야기 같구나, 남자라!
Same old story.
A man!
아뇨, 그런 뜻이 아녜요
No, I don't mean like that.
하지만 그는 실재해요
전 그를 보았어요
But he's real.
I've seen him.
그를 만났죠
딱 한번이지만
I've met him. just once.
그러고 전 그가 날아가게
그냥 뒀어요
And then I let him fly away.
뭐, 얘기 끝났네
Well, there you are.
가서 그를 찾으렴
Go and find him.
노력해 봤어요
I've tried.
- 그는 없어요
- 얘야!
- He's nowhere.
- Hey!
포기하다니 별 일을 다 보겠구나
Not like you to give up.
네가 여섯살 쯤 때가
기억나는구나
I remember when you was about six years
old, your mother said, 'No holiday this year.'
네 엄마가 말했지
'올해는 휴가 못 간다'
그래서 넌 혼자 걸어나와선
스트레스클라이드까지 버스를 탔지!
So off you toddled all on your own,
and you got on a bus to Strathclyde!
우린 경찰을 부르고 난리도 아녔고!
We had the police out and everything!
그 애는 어디갔니, 응?
Where's she gone, then?
그 여자애는 어디로 숨었니?
Where's that girl? Eh?
할아버지가 맞아요
You're right.
그는 여전히 저 어딘가에
있을테니까요, 어딘가에요
Cos he's still out there, somewhere.
그를 찾아낼 거에요, 할아버지
And I'll find him, Gramps.
100년 동안 기다려야 한대도..
Even if I have to wait 100 years...
그를 찾을 거에요
...I'll find him.
오, 멋지구리하군
Oh, fascinating.
바이오플립 디지털 스위치인것
같아, 특별히 고안된..
Seems to be a bioflip digital stitch,
specifically for...
내가 차 쓸 차례잖니
It's my turn for the car.
그건 뭣하러 쓰게?
What do you need it for?
잠깐 휴가좀 가려구요
A quick getaway.
좋은 아침!
Morning!
잘들 보고 있어
그녀는 돌아올 테니까
Keep an eye out. She'll come back.
곧 그녀는 내 것이야
And then she's mine.
내일 봅시다
See you tomorrow.
지금은 안 돼!
Not now!
차가 필요하다니까
너 어디니?
I need the car. Where are you?
안돼요, 지금 바빠!
I can't. I'm busy!
왜 속닥거려?
Why are you whispering?
교회에 있어
I'm in church.
교회에는 뭐하러 갔니?
What are you doing in church?
기도하러!
Praying!
하! 회개하긴 늦었네요, 아가씨
Hah!
Bit late for that, madam.
교회에는 뭐하러 갔다냐?
What's she in church for?
쉿, 아버지!
언덕에나 올라 가세요
Hush, you! Go up the hill.
하지만 차가 필요하대두
But I need the car.
수제트와 놀러 갈거야
I'm going out with Suzette.
수요일 모임 애들한테
다 말했나봐
She's asked all the Wednesday girls.
아디포스 약을 먹는 중인데
완전 멋있게 변했다나봐
She's been on those Adipose pills,
she says she looks marvellous.
여기 있는거 알아요, 그러니까
쉽게쉽게 나오지 그래요?
We know you're in here, so why don't
you make this nice and easy and show yourself?
기다리고 있어요
I'm waiting.
경고하는데
난 인내력이 많지 않아요
I warn you, I'm not a patient woman.
자, 나오시지
Now, out you come.
좋아요, 거친 방법으로 가죠
Right,
we'll do it the hard way.
그녀를 잡아!
Get her!
여기 계시는군
There you are.
기록들을 조사해 봤어요, 포스터 씨
당신네 보고들은 전부 가짜였어요
I've been through the records, Foster,
and all of your results have been faked.
알약에 관한 뭔가가
공개되지 않고 있어요
There's something about those
pills you're not telling us.
오, 내 생각에 이 인터뷰는
내가 주도하는 것 같은데, 페니
Oh, I think I'll be conducting
this interview, Penny.
당신들은 이럴 권한 없어
You've got no right to do this.
이거 놔!
Let me go!
이건 말도 안 돼
This is ridiculous.
거기 앉게
Sit there.
- 편집장님께 전화하겠어요
- 앉으라니까
- I'm phoning my editor.
- I said sit.
'날 묶을 수는 없어!'
'You can't tie me up! '
대체 이 나라가
어떤 줄이나 알아요?
What sort of a country do you think this is?
오, 아름답도록 뚱뚱한 나라지
Oh, it's a beautifully fat country.
난 이 정도의 비만도를
찾기 위해 먼 거리를 여행했어
I've travelled a long way to
find obesity on this scale.
좋아요, 그럼, 포스터 씨
So come on, then, Miss Foster.
저 알약들, 대체 뭐에요?
Those pills, what are they?
음, 너도 좀 알고 있어야겠지
어차피 기사는 쓰지도 못할테니까
Well, you might as well have a scoop,
since you'll never see it printed.
이건 '생명의 불꽃'이야
This is the spark of life.
그게 대체 무슨 뜻인데요?
And what's that supposed to mean?
공식적으론, 캡슐이 모든 지방
세포를 끌어들여서 배출되는거지
Officially, the capsule attracts
all the fat cells and flushes them away.
그래, 확실히 끌어들여
Well, it certainly attracts them.
그 부분은 사실이야
That part's true.
하지만 그것은 지방을 모아서
자극해 '몸'형태를 만들지
But it binds the fat together
and galvanises it to form a body.
저, '몸'이라니 무슨 뜻이에요?
Well, what do you mean 'a body'?
내 이름에 관해서 묻지 않다니
놀랐는걸. 잘 골랐는데
I am surprised you never asked
about my name. I chose it well.
포스터 란,
'포스터 마더(유모)' 지
Foster, as in foster mother.
그리고 이것들은..
And these...
나의 아이들이야
...are my children.
웃기지 말아요
You're kidding me.
저게 대체 뭐에요?
What the hell is that?
아디포스야
Adipose.
'아디포스'라고 불리지
It's called an Adipose.
산 지방으로 만들어졌어
Made out of living fat.
도나!
닥터!
뭐, 뭐 하고 있는..
오, 이런, 세상에!
어떻게..?
나야!
그래, 보고 있잖아
이거 진짜 끝내주네!
대체 거기서 뭐 하고 있는거야?
당신을 찾고 있었어!
왜?
신문 스크랩..
휴일들..
시코락스..
전부 모았더니..
모두 화제가.. 당신이었어!
당신이라고!
저희가 방해했나요?
Are we interrupting you?
튀어!
여자를 잡아!
Get her!
저 자도!
And him!
난 어쩌구요?
What about me?
오, 맙소사
믿기지 않아!
Oh, my God, I don't believe it!
심지어 양복도 똑같은 걸
입었잖아
You've even got the same suit.
당신은 바뀌지도 않아?
Don't you ever change?
그래, 고마워, 도나
지금은 좀 빼자
Yeah, thanks Donna, not right now.
옛날 생각 나지!
just like old times!
생각해 봤거든, '어떻게
닥터를 찾을 수 있지?'
Cos I thought, 'How do you find the Doctor? '
그러다가 생각났어, '사건을
찾아 다니면 그가 나타날 거야'
Then I thought, 'Look for trouble, and he'll turn up.'
모든 곳을 돌아봤어, 말만 해봐
I looked everywhere, you name it-
UFO 목격, 크롭 서클, 해중
괴물들.. 모두 찾아다녔어
UFO sightings, crop circles, sea monsters...
I found them all.
벌들이 사라진다던가 하면,
난 생각했지, '그가 관련됐어'
Like the bees disappearing,
I thought, 'He's connected.'
중요한건 이거야, 닥터
이제 그것들을 다 믿어
Cos the thing is, Doctor, I believe it all now.
당신이 내 눈을 틔워줬어,
저 밖의 모든 놀라운 것들
You opened my eyes. All those amazing
things out there, I believe them all.
그것들을 모두 믿어
버킹엄 궁전 위를 날아간
그 타이타닉 골수 팬은 말고
Apart from that replica of the Titanic
flying over Buckingham Palace. That's a hoax.
크리스마스 날에 말이지
그 자들은 완전 미쳤어
무슨 말이야
벌들이 사라진다니?
What do you mean, the bees are disappearing?
나도 모르겠어
인터넷에 그렇게 적혀있더라고
That's what it says on the internet.
어쨌든간에 아디포스 물산에 관해
음모설이 떠돌더라고
그래서 봐야겠다 싶었지
There were conspiracy theories about
Adipose Industries, so I thought I'd look.
- 올라타!
- 뭐, 거기에?
In you get! What, in that thing?
But theyll just call us back up again.
하지만 저 자들이
우리를 다시 뒤쫓아 올 거야
조종기를 소닉 케이지로 잠갔어
나만이 조종할 수 있지
I've locked the controls with
a sonic cage. Only I can control it.
그녀가 소닉 장치를
갖고있지 않은 이상 말야
Not unless she's got a sonic device.
그럴리는 없고
Which is very unlikely.
저리 비켜
Out of my way.
오, 그렇게는 안 되지
Oh, I don't think so.
됐다
Come on.
창문으로 들어갈 수 있어
We can get in through the window.
건물을 잠가
Deadlock the building.
열리질 않아!
Can't get it open!
그럼 뽀개면 되지!
We'll smash it, then!
선을 끊고 있어!
She's cutting the cable!
도나!
Donna!
- 닥터! / 꽉 잡아!
- 그러고 있잖아!
- Doctor!
- Hold on! - I am!
닥터!
Doctor!
이제 다른 한 쪽도 끊어야지
And now for the other one.
떨어지겠어!
I'm going to fall!
대체 무슨 일이지?
What the hell is going on?!
다 당신 잘못이야!
This is all your fault.
집에 있었어야 했어!
I should've stayed at home!
곧 돌아올게!
I won't be a minute!
그래, 제법 꾀가 좋네
저 자는 말야
Yes, he's slippery, that one.
이제 누군지나 알아내 보자
Time we found out who he is.
- 대체 뭔 일인지 말해줄래요?
- 당신 기자에요? / 그런데요
Is anyone gonna tell me what's going on?
- You a journalist?
- Yes.
그럼, 지어 내시라고요
Well, make it up.
저리 가!
Get off!
내가 잡았어, 잡았다고
I've got you. I've got you.
발좀 그만 차!
Stop kicking!
내가 맞았어. 당신이랑 있으면
맨날 이렇지, 그치?
I was right. It's always like this with you, in it?
오, 그래! 이제 가자!
Oh, yes! And off we go!
이봐요!
Oi!
미안요!
Sorry!
이제 스스로 좀 하시죠
나가요
Now do yourself a favour, get out.
자, 그럼. 결국 만났군요
Well, then. At last.
- 안녕하세요
- 만나서 반가워요
- Hello.
- Nice to meet you.
- 닥터입니다
- 도나에요
- I'm the Doctor.
- And I'm Donna.
범죄 콤비로군
Partners in crime.
- 분명히 외계인이겠군요, 소닉
기술로 봤을 때 말이죠 / 오, 맞다!
And evidently off world, judging
by your sonic technology.
Oh yeah,
I've still got your sonic pen.
여전히 당신의
소닉 펜을 갖고있지요
멋져요! 맘에 드네. 통통해.
확실히 통통한 것 같아
Nice! I like it. Sleek,
it's kind of sleek.
Oh, it's definitely sleek.
오, 확실히 통통하네요
진짜 이름을 서명하시려면
어떻게 되시는지요?
And if you were to sign your real name,
that would be?
코필리아 유모에요, 5연합
클라사빈디 간호 육아소에서 왔죠
Matron Cofelia,
of the Five-Straighten Classabindi Nursery Fleet.
- 전은하적 직위에요
- 영아 간호사군
- Intergalactic Class.
- A wet nurse.
인간들을 대리모로 쓰고있구만
Using humans as surrogates.
아디포스의 선조들로부터
새로운 세대를 양육하도록 고용되었어요
I've been employed by the Adiposian first family to
foster a new generation after their breeding planet was lost.
그들의 양육 행성이 실종 된 다음에요
잃어버렸다구요?
어떻게 행성을 '잃어'버릴 수가 있죠?
How do you lose a planet?
오, 정치 쪽에는 관심 없어요
Oh, the politics are none of my concern.
전 그저 부모들을 대신해 아이들을
여기서 돌볼 뿐이랍니다
I'm just here to take care of the
children on behalf of the parents.
뭐,외우주의 슈퍼 유모 같은 거에요?
What, like an outer space Supernanny?
네, 그게 맘에 드신다면야
Yes, if you like.
저.. 그 조그만 것들 말예요
지방으로 만들어지는 거죠?
So... So those little things,
they're made out of fat, yeah?
하지만 이 여자, 스테이시 캠벨은
남은게 하나도 없었어요
But that woman, Stacy Campbell,
there was nothing left of her.
위기상황엔, 아디포스는 뼈와
털, 내부 장기도 변환할 수 있어요
Oh, in a crisis, the Adipose can
convert bone and hair and internal organs.
조금 아프게 만들지만요
불쌍한 것들
Makes them a little bit sick, poor things.
불쌍한 스테이시는 어떻구요?
What about poor Stacy?
레벨 5 행성을 착취하는 것은
은하 법에 어긋나는데요
Seeding a level five planet
is against galactic law.
협박하는 거에요?
Are you threatening me?
도와드리려고
그러는 거에요, 유모님
I'm trying to help you, Matron.
이번이 유일한 기회에요
This is your one chance.
이걸 받아들이지 않으면
제가 당신을 멈춰야 하니까요
Cos if you don't call this off,
then I'll have to stop you.
총알도 멈출 수 있을것
같진 않은데요
I hardly think you can stop bullets.
잠깐, 잠깐, 잠깐만요
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
하나만 더요, 죽기 전에
One more thing - before dying.
동일한 소닉 장치들을 서로 반대로
들면 어떻게 되는지 알아요?
Do you know what happens if you hold two
identical sonic devices against each other?
아뇨
No.
나도 몰라요
해 봅시다!
Nor me. Let's find out.
가자!
Come on!
출산 계획을 앞당겨야겠다
I'm advancing the birth plan.
예비 노동력을 이용한다
We're going into premature labour.
'세포 유화' 로군
Cellular bossification.
- 여자를 묶어
- 왜 이런담
- Tie her up.
- Oh, you're kidding me.
그것도 괜찮은데
That's one solution.
창고에 숨는다라
마음에 들어!
Hide in a cupboard. I like it!
종일 이걸 해킹하고 있었어
유모가 컴퓨터 코어를
I've been hacking into this all day,
cos the Matron's got a computer core
running through the building, triple-deadlocked.
빌딩에 관통하게 해 놨어
3중 보안이야
이제는 이게 있으니
들어갈 수 있겠네
But now I've got this, I can get into it.
그건 뭐하는 거에요?
What does that thing do?
유도기야
(출산 유도기)
It's the inducer.
원래 100만명을 이용하려고 했지
We had planned to seed millions.
하지만 그 남자가 외계인인데다
그림자 원칙을 들먹였으니
But if that man's an alien and he's alerted the Shadow
Proclamation, then the first one million humans will have to do.
우선 10만명만 가지고도
될 거야
그자를 찾아
여자도
Find him, and the woman.
시간낭비 하지 말고
바로 죽여
Don't waste time, just kill them.
건물 전체를 감아올렸군
She's wired up the whole building.
프라이버시 좀 보호받자고
And we need a bit of privacy.
기절시킬 정도로만 말이지
just enough to stun them.
하지만 왜 타워 부분을
감아놨지?
But why's she wired up a tower block?
이게 다 뭐 하는 걸까?
What's it all for?
'유도기 접속합니다'
'Inducer online.'
나이가 든 것 같은걸
You look older.
고마워
Thanks.
여전히 혼자 다녀?
Still on your own?
응, 아, 아니다. 친구가 있었어
마사, 이름이 마사 존스야
Yep. Well, no. I had this friend. Martha,
she was called, Martha Jones. She was brilliant.
정말 괜찮은 여자였어
그런데 난 그녀의 인생을
반은 망쳐 놨지
And I destroyed half her life.
그렇지만 잘 지내
괜찮아
But she's fine, she's good.
그녀는 떠났어
She's gone.
- 로즈는?
- 여전히 실종이야
- What about Rose?
- Still lost.
난 당신이 세계여행을 할 줄 알았어
I thought you were gonna travel the world.
말이야 쉬웠지
Easier said than done.
그러니까, 당신과 하루 있고 나서
난 내가 바뀔 줄 알았지
It's like, I had that one day with
you and I was gonna change.
해볼 것들이 참 많았어
I was gonna do so much.
그런데 다음날 아침 일어났더니
똑같은 일상인거야
And then I woke up the next morning,
same old life.
마치 당신은 없었던 것처럼
It's like you were never there.
노력했어
정말 노력해 봤어
And I tried, I did try.
이집트로 갔지
맨발로 걷고 뭐 그럴 작정이었어
I went to Egypt.
I was gonna go barefoot and everything.
하지만 버스 타고 다니고,
가이드 북도 보고, 물도 잘 마시고
Then it's all bus trips and guidebooks and don't
drink the water, and two weeks later, you're back at home.
그러다 2주가 갔고
집에 와 있더라구
당신과 있는 거랑은
비교가 안 돼
It's nothing like being with you.
- 내가 미쳤지, 그 얘기를 거절하다니
- 무슨 이야기?
- I must've been mad, turning down that offer.
- What offer?
당신과 같이 가자는 거
To come with you.
나랑 같이 간다고?
You're coming with me?
오, 그래, 부탁이야!
Oh, yes, please!
... 그래
Right.
'유도기 활성화합니다.'
'Inducer activated.'
저게 뭘 하는 거지?
What's it doing now?
그녀가 프로그램을 가동시켰어
She started the program.
'유도기 전송합니다'
'Inducer transmitting.'
기록해 놓으시라고, 카터 양
Mark the date, Miss Carter.
생일 축하한다고
Happy birthday.
10만의 생일들을
One million birthdays.
진심이야, 아디포스 알약은
정말 최고야
I swear, that Adipose treatment is fabulous.
내 볼살좀 봐봐
just look at my chin.
그리고 복부에도 좋아
벌써 두 사이즈나 줄였다니까
And it's very good for back fat,
I'm down two sizes.
마치 기적같아
조그만 알약 하나 가지고 이렇다니
It's like a miracle. All that from just one little pill.
게다가 난 평상시처럼 먹고 있거든
And I've been eating like normal.
괜찮니, 얘?
You all right, love?
그래, 그냥 좀..
Yeah, I'm just...
기분이 좀 이상하네
무슨 이건..
Funny sort of feeling, like it's...
무슨 일이야?
What's happened?
잘 모르겠어
아마도 그러니까..
I'm not sure. it just seems to be...
화장실 좀 갔다 올게
Better pop to the loo.
- 세상에, 수제트!
- 왜?
- Oh, my God, Suzette!
- What?
이게 뭐야? 떨어져!
What is it?! Get it off me!
내게 오렴, 얘들아
나에게로 와!
Come to me, children. Come to me.
모두들 물러서세요
저들을 만지지 말아요
Everyone get back, don't touch them.
여태까진 무게를 줄이는 수준이었지만
유모가 비상 생식을 가동시켰어
So far they're just losing weight, but the
Matron's gone up to emergency parthenogenesis.
그러면 뭐에서 탄생하는데?
And that's when they convert?
뼈, 장기, 모든 것들이지
Skeletons, organs, everything.
10만 명이 죽게 생겼어!
A million people are gonna die!
전송을 취소해야겠어
Gotta cancel the signal.
이게 원래 신호를 갖고 있으니까
This contains the primary signal.
저걸 끌 수만 있다면, 지방은
다시 평범하게 돌아가겠지
If I can switch it off,
the fat goes back to being just fat.
용쓰는군 그래
A nice try.
두배로 올려야지
Double strength.
'유도기 강화됩니다'
'Inducer increasing.'
안돼, 안돼, 안돼
두배로 강화했어, 그게 필요한데..
No, no, no, no, no, she's doubled it, I need...
시간이 없어!
Haven't got time.
너무 멀리 있어
막아낼 수 없다구
It's too far, I can't override it.
저들이 죽게 될거야!
They're all gonna die!
내가 뭐 도와줄 거 없어?
Is there anything I can do?
미안하지만 이건
당신 할 수 있는 일이 아냐
Sorry, this is way beyond you.
기반 신호도 두배로
올려야 되는데..
Gotta double the base pulse...
닥터, 말해달라고
당신 뭐가 필요해?
Doctor, tell me, what do you need?
취소를 가속화시킬
두 번째 캡슐이 필요해
I need a second capsule to boost the override,
but I've only got the one. I can't save them!
하지만 난 하나밖에 없다고
저들을 구할 수 없어!
멈췄다
그것들이 사라졌어!
- It's stopped.
- They've gone.
무슨 일이에요?
What's happened?
'닥터'가 일어난 것 같군
I think the Doctor happened.
어차피 그래도
1만 마리의 아디포스는 됐어
But we've still given birth to 10,000 Adipose.
'육아소'가 오고 있구나
And the Nursery is coming.
저게 대체 뭐에요?
What the hell was that?
내 집으로 가는 차야
It s my lift home.
날 그냥 버려놓고 가지 마요!
You cant just leave me here!
이제 멈췄군
It just stopped.
대체 이번에는 뭐래?
What on earth is it now?
멈췄다
Fine.
'육아소'이라고 한거 말야
노팅 힐에 있는 탁아소는 아니지?
When you say 'nursery',
you don't mean a cr?he in Notting Hill?
육아 우주선이야
Nursery ship.
'신호 수신합니다'
'Incoming signal.'
가서 저들을 멈추는 게
낫지 않을까?
Hadn't we better go and stop them?
아디포스 선조들에게서 오는
지시들이야
Instructions from the Adiposian first family.
아가들아! 오, 내 아가들아
조금만 참으렴
Children! Oh, my children, behold.
내가 집으로 데려다 줄게
I am taking you home.
저 먼 우주에서 너희들의
새로운 아빠엄마가 기다리고 있단다
Far across the galaxy,
your new mummies and daddies are waiting.
이제 날아가자!
And you will fly!
올라가거라, 아가들아
올라가!
Up you go, babies. Up you go!
그래 잘 한다,
집으로 날아가!
That's it, fly away home!
타워 부분을 감아 올린 건
부양의 매개로 바꾸기 위해서였어
She's wired up the tower block
to convert it into a levitation post.
오~
Ooh! Ooh!
지금 곤란에 처한건
우리만이 아닌가 본데
We're not the ones in trouble now.
저 여자도야!
She is!
데려가 줘요
아이들에겐 내가 필요해요!
Take me. The children need me!
그럼 어떻게 할 거야?
What you gonna do, then?
- 저들을 쓸어버릴거야?
- 그래봤자 아이들이잖아
- Blow them up?
- They're just children.
자기들 고향에도
별 도움 안 될거야
They can't help where they came from.
지난 번 하고는 좀 달라졌네
That makes a change from last time.
마사란 사람이 당신을
좋게 만들었나봐
That Martha must've done you good.
아, 그랬지
그래, 그래, 정말 그랬어
Ah, she did. Yeah, yeah, she did.
그녀는 날 좋아했지
She fancied me.
미친 마사네, 그럼
Mad Martha, that one.
눈먼 마사,
헤픈 마사
Blind Martha. Charity Martha.
내가 지방한테 인사를 하고 있네
I'm waving at fat.
사실, 다이어트 용으로는
효과가 좋았던 것 같아
Actually, as a diet plan,
it sort of works. There she is!
저기 있다!
코필리아 유모, 내 말좀 들어요!
Matron Cofelia, listen to me!
그러기 싫은데, 닥터
Oh, I don't think so, Doctor.
어차피 당신을 영영 볼일은
절대 없을 테니까
And if I never see you again,
it'll be too soon.
왜 아무도 내 말을 안 듣지?
Why does no-one ever listen?
도와드리려 한다니까요!
I'm trying to help!
얼른 지붕으로 건너와요
just get across to the roof.
부양 광선을
거스를 수 있겠어요?
Can you shift the levitation beam?
뭐, 나를 체포하게?
What, so that you can arrest me?
아디포스들의 지시를 보았어요
I saw the Adiposian instructions -
그들도 범죄인 걸 알고 있어요
지구에서의 양육행위가요
they know it's a crime, breeding on earth.
그럼 이제 뭘 없애고 싶어하겠어?
자기들의 공범자지!
So what's the one thing they
want to get rid of? Their accomplice!
난 공범자 이상이야
I'm far more than that.
나는 이 아이들의 유모라고
I'm nanny to all these children.
엄마아빠가 아이들을 받았으니
유모가 더이상 필요 없다니까!
Mum and Dad have got the kids now,
they don't need the nanny anymore.
거기, 두 사람!
당신들 미쳤어
Oi, you two! Youre just mad.
내 말 들려? 미쳤다고!
Do you hear me? Mad!
그리고 당신들을
보고할거야
And I'm gonna report you for...
미쳤다고!
madness!
이것 봐, 어떤 사람들은
이런 걸 받아들이지 못해
You see, some people just can't take it.
어떤 사람들은 되고
And some people can.
자, 그럼..
So, then...
타디스!
Tardis!
가자!
Come on!
내 차잖아!
That's my car!
이건 운명같은걸
That is like destiny.
이럴 준비를 해 놓았지
And I've been ready for this.
오래 전에 짐을 싸 놨어
만일을 대비해서
I packed ages ago, just in case.
내 생각에, 더운 날씨, 추운 날씨,
상관 없는 날씨
Cos I thought, hot weather, cold weather, no
weather... he goes anywhere, I've gotta be prepared.
그는 어디든지 가니까
내가 준비해 놔야지
모자 상자도 있네
You've got a hatbox.
모자의 행성이라지
난 준비됐어!
Planet of the Hats, I'm ready!
예방접종도 맞아야 될까?
Do I need injections?
캄보디아에 갈 때처럼 말야
그런게 필요한가?
Like when you go to Cambodia,
is there any of that?
왜냐면 내 친구 비나가
바레인에 갔을 때 말야..
Cos my friend Veena went to Bahrain, and...
말이 별로 없네
You're not saying much.
아니, 단지..
No, it's just...
- 타디스 생활은 알잖아
- 날 원하지 않는구나
- It's a funny old life, in the Tardis.
- You don't want me.
그런 얘기는 아니었어
I'm not saying that.
나한테 같이가자고 했잖아
But you asked me.
혼자가 더 좋다 이거야?
Would you rather be on your own?
아니야
No.
정말로 아니야
Actually, no.
하지만..
But...
최근에, 마사랑,
내가 얘기 했겠지만..
The last time, with Martha,
like I said...
좀 복잡하게 끝났어
...it got complicated.
전부 내 잘못이었고
And that was all my fault.
친구가 하나 필요할 뿐야
I just want a mate.
나랑 결혼하고 싶다고?!
(mate: 결혼하다)
You just want TO MATE?!
'친구'가 필요하다니까!
I just want A mate!
나랑 결혼할 순 없어, 능구렁이야!
You're not mating with me, sunshine!
친구라고, 친구가 필요하대도!
A mate, I want a mate!
잘도 그렇겠지, 왜냐면
그런 속임수엔 넘어가지 않거든
just as well,
because I'm not having any of that nonsense.
당신은 그래봤자 쭉정이에 불과해
외계인 쭉정이
I mean,
you're just a long streak of nothing, alien nothing.
됐나보네, 그럼, 알았어
There we are, then. OK.
- 가도 돼?
- 그래
- I can come?
- Yeah.
당연히 되지, 그래
나도 좋은걸
Course you can, yeah. I'd love it.
오, 정말 이건..!
차 열쇠!
Ohh, that's just! Car keys!
뭐라고?
What?
아직도 엄마의 차 열쇠를
갖고 있었어!
I've still got my mum's car keys!
곧 돌아올게
I won't be a minute.
알아, 엄마, 나도 봤어
조그만 지방들 말야
I know, Mum, I saw it, little fat people.
나 가야겠어, 비나랑
한동안 지낼 것 같아
I've got to go.
I'm going to stay with Veena for a bit.
'하늘에 떠 있었잖니'
'It was in the sky.'
나도 알아, 우주선이지
I know, spaceship.
하지만 차 열쇠는 주고 가야지
But I've still got the car keys.
브룩 가 코너에서 30피트 정도에
쓰레기통이 있어. 거기에 놓아 둘게
There's a bin on Brook Street 30 feet from
the corner, I'm going to leave them in there.
- '뭐? 깡통?'
- 그래, 쓰레기통이라니까
- 'What? A bin?
- ' Yes, I said 'bin'.
'그럴 순 없잖니'
'You can't do that.
오, 불평좀 그만 해
차는 조금 더 가면 길에 있어
Oh, stop complaining,
the car's just down the road a bit.
가야 돼, 정말로 가야 돼
Got to go, really got to go.
- 안녕
- '하지만 도나, 그럴 순..'
- Bye.
- 'But Donna, you can't... '
조금 이따가 올 여자가 있어요
키크고 금발인 여자, 실비아에요
There's this woman that's going to come along,
tall blond woman called Sylvia, tell her that bin there.
바로 저 쓰레기통이라고 전해주세요
그러면 될 거에요
저 쓰레기통이에요
It'll make sense. That bin there.
그럼 출발하자고!
Off we go, then!
잘 왔어, 타디스야
Here it is, the Tardis.
안쪽이 바깥쪽 보다 크지
Bigger on the inside than it is on the outside.
오, 그 대사는 다 알아
Oh, I know all that bit.
어쨌든 솔직히,
난방 좀 켜 주라
Although frankly,
you could turn the heating up.
자, 이 넓은 우주에서-
So, whole wide universe -
어디로 가고 싶어?
where do you want to go?
- 정확히 어디로 갈 지 알아
- 어딘데?
I know exactly the place. Which is?
저 쪽으로 2.5 마일
Two and a half miles that way.
도나!
그 날아다니는 파란 상자야!
Donna! It's the flying blue box!
뭐지?
What?
저건 도나잖아
도나야
That's Donna. That's Donna.
그리고 그 남자네! 그 남자야!
And that's him! That's him!
가거라, 얘야,
저 위로 날아가!
Go on, girl! Go on, get up there!
Hey...
- 고대 로마야
- 환상적이야
그것이 왔다, 파란 상자가
가장 끔찍한 일들이 보여요
계집들의 예언은
편협하고 두루뭉술해
오직 남자들만이 진정한
인식의 능력을 가지니까
어디에서 바람이 부는지
말씀드릴게요
닥터, 당신은 불운을 가져왔어요
우린 신들께 계시받은
미래를 세우는 것이다
네가 누군지 내게
말할것을 명한다
닥터!
하늘이 무너진다!
우린 폼페이에 있어
그리고 오늘은 폭발일이야
DC 영드갤 돗치우드
dotchwood@gmail.com